接下来我们想知道地点
Next we want to understand the location
以及这个错误的原因。
and the cause of the bug.
在这里，我们可以用科学的方法。
And, here, to do that we can use the scientific method.
换句话说，首先，研究数据——理解数据
In other words, first, study the data-- understand the data
我们得到的。
that we've got.
做出假设——猜测错误可能是什么。
Make hypotheses-- guesses about what the bug could be.
做一个实验来验证这个假设，然后重复。
Do an experiment to test the hypothesis, and repeat.
再说一遍，我们想研究数据。
So again-- we want to study the data.
所以我们想看看这个测试输入
So we want to look at that test input that
导致错误和不正确的结果，以及失败的断言，
causes the bug and the incorrect results, and failed assertions,
堆栈跟踪和它引起的异常。
and stack traces, and exceptions that it causes.
这些都是数据告诉我们--给我们信息
Those are all data that tell us-- give us information
关于虫子可能是什么。
about what the bug might be.
所以我们想先仔细研究一下。
So we want to study those carefully first.
然后我们想提出一个一致的假设
And then we want to come up with a hypothesis that's consistent
有了关于窃听器可能在哪里的数据，
with the data about where the bug might be,
不可能的地方。
and where it cannot be.
先把这个假设概括一下是很好的。
It's good to make this hypothesis general at first.
第三，我们想设计一个实验
Third, we want to devise an experiment
来检验这个假设。
to test the hypothesis.
做这个实验真的很好
And it's really good to make this experiment
只是一个观察。
just an observation.
换言之，探测，如打印语句或中断
In other words, a probe, like a print statement or a break
收集信息但干扰系统的点
point that collects information but disturbs the system
尽可能少。
as little as possible.
特别是，这个实验不应该
Particularly, this experiment should not
“好吧，让我彻底重写
be "well, let me completely rewrite
这个函数的主体，看看它是否修复了错误。”
the body of this function and see if that fixes the bug."
你首先要做的是真正理解
What you want to do first is really understand
我们的假设是否正确。
whether our hypothesis is true.
在那次实验之后，我们得到了更多的数据。
After that experiment, we've got more data.
把我们收集的数据加到实验中，
Add that data we collected to the experiment,
从我们以前知道的。
from what we knew before.
做一个新的假设。
And make a fresh hypothesis.
所以希望我们排除了一些可能性，
So hopefully we've ruled out some possibilities,
可能会缩小可能的地点范围
and maybe narrowed down the set of possible locations
以及错误的原因。
and reasons for the bug.
因此，让我们在这个
So let's look at these steps in the context of this most
我们在上一节中使用的常见单词示例。
common word example that we had in the previous section.
现在我们充实了它。
Now we fleshed it out.
最常见的一个词并不是独自完成它的工作。
The most common word doesn't do its job all by itself.
相反，它有这三个助手函数。
Instead it has these three helper functions.
这一个，它接受文本字符串
This one, that takes the string of text
把它拆分成单词--所以它返回
and splits it into words-- so it returns
列表中每个元素都是一个单词的列表。
a list in which each element of the list is a word.
计算出现次数，这需要一个单词列表--
Count occurrences, that takes a list of words--
很可能是那句话--
probably the one returned by split into words--
并生成频率图。
and produces a frequency map.
所以对于列表中的每个单词，这张地图
So for each word in that list, this map
会有一个有那个词的条目
will have an entry that has that word, along
以及该单词在列表中出现的次数。
with the number of times that that word occurs in that list.
然后是第三个helper函数
And then the third helper function
获取其中一个频率图
takes one of these frequency maps
基本上找到了它的顶点--找到了单词，
and basically finds the peaks in it-- finds the words,
查找具有最高整数的字符串。
finds the strings that have the highest integer.
事实上，它发现了这样一个词。
In fact, it finds one such word.
所以如果有领带，它会给你
So if there are ties, it's going to give you
一个特别的词。
one particular word.
因为我们只想要一个最大限度地出现的词。
Because we only wanted a word that occurs in maximally.
我们不一定都需要。
We don't necessarily need all of them.
所以在最普通的字眼里，你会
And so inside most common word, you'll
看它叫这三个帮手
see that it's calling these three helper
方法——基本上取一个的输出，
methods-- basically taking the output of one,
把它作为输入传递给下一个，
passing it in as the input to the next,
直到我们最终得到这个获胜的词
until we finally get this winning word which
是我们真正的回报。
is what we actual return.
我们这里有点点点
And we've got dot-dot-dots here just
因为还有其他Java代码
because there's other Java code that we
需要把这个粘在一起。
need to glue this together.
但对于这个例子来说，这并不重要。
But it won't be important for the sake of this example.
所以首先我们要研究数据。
So first we want to study the data.
我们得到的一种重要的数据形式
One important form of data we get
是来自异常的堆栈跟踪。
is a stack trace from an exception.
所以你应该练习读取堆栈跟踪
So you should practice reading stack traces
你可以在Eclipse和Java中看到，因为它们会给你
you see in Eclipse and Java, because they'll give you
大量的信息
an enormous amount of information
关于虫子可能在哪里和什么地方。
about where and what the bug might be.
例如，堆栈跟踪可能会告诉您
The stack trace, for instance, might tell you
它实际上是在倒计时出现。
that it's actually down inside count occurrences.
那就是我们可能想要集中注意力的地方。
And then that is where we maybe want to focus our attention.
不过，也有可能是
Although, it could also have been
由于拼字错误引起的
caused by a mistake in split into words
然后就变成了计数事件，对吧？
that then fed into count occurrences, right?
但它不可能是最常见的，
But it can't be in find most common,
因为那已经被执行了。
Because that has an even executed yet.
确实如此——堆栈跟踪给了我们信息
So that really does-- that stack trace gives us information
关于虫子能在哪里，不能在哪里。
about where the bug can and cannot be.
分离小测试用例的过程
The process of isolating a small test case
也可能给我们以前没有的数据。
may also give us data that we didn't have before.
我们甚至可能有两个相关的测试用例
We may even have two related test cases
从某种意义上说，这是一个错误
that bracket the bug, in the sense that one of them
成功而其中一个失败。
succeeds and one of them fails.
所以也许把这个字符串转换成最常用的单词
So maybe passing this string into most common word
失败，但此字符串成功。
fails, but this string succeeds.
然后你可以看看这两者的区别
And then you can look at the difference between these two
测试用例，然后查看——并获取一些信息
test cases, and see-- and get some information
关于问题的可能原因。
about the possible cause of problem.
所以这是另一个为什么通过减少你的测试来隔离
So this is another reason why isolating by reducing your test
输入——减少导致错误的输入——可以给您
input-- reducing the input the causes the bug-- can give you
关于这个错误的更多信息
a lot more information about the bug
甚至连代码都没看。
without even looking at any of the code yet.
现在我们要假设。
Now we want to hypothesize.
为了这个，你可以想想
And for this, It can help to think
关于作为模块的程序。
about the program as modules.
记住，最常见的单词有三个子例程
Remember that most common word has three subroutines
它正在使用。
that it's using.
这些子程序之间有数据流
And there's a flow of data between those subroutines
这是由最常见的词编排的。
that's orchestrated by most common words.
如果bug的症状是一个异常
Now if the symptom of the bug is an exception
像我们刚才说的那样，在计数事件中，
in count occurrences, like we said earlier,
然后我们可以排除下游的一切。
then we can rule out everything that's downstream.
窃听器实际上必须发生在这里或这里，
The bug actually has to happen either here or here,
但这段代码还没有运行。
but this code hasn't even run yet.
所以虫子不会在这里出现。
So the bug doesn't occur here.
所以我们可以选择一个假设
So we might choose a hypothesis that
尝试进一步本地化错误。
tries to localize the bug even further.
例如，我们可以假设
We might, for instance, hypothesize
窃听器一分为二，
that the bug is in split in two words,
破坏其结果，从而导致异常
corrupting its results which then cause the exception
并计算出现次数。
and count occurrences.
所以我们想要一个实验来验证这个假设。
So we then want an experiment to test that hypothesis.
例如，我们可以将print语句放在split的末尾
For instance, we might put print statements at the end of split
说出来看看它到底在生产什么。
into words to see what it's actually producing.
或者我们可以将额外的断言语句分成
Or we might put extra assertion statements into split
用语言表达。
into words.
如果我们的假设是真的
Now if our hypothesis is true and there is actually
垃圾结果或损坏的结果，
garbage results, or corrupt results,
分裂成语言或生产，我们
split into words or producing, we
将排除计数事件
will have ruled out count occurrences
作为问题的根源，我们可以集中精力
as the source of the problem, and we can focus
相反的，是分裂成文字。
instead on split into words.
如果我们的程序是错误的，就把它分成几个字
If our process is false, and split into words
是返回好的数据，然后我们可以排除分成几个词
is returning good data, then we can rule out split into words
我们会把重点放在反事故上。
and we'd focus on counter occurrences.
好的实验是温和的观察
Now a good experiment is a gentle observation
对系统没有太大的干扰。
of the system that doesn't disturb it much.
它可能试图运行另一个测试用例。
It might be trying to run a different test case.
当我们讨论测试用例的时候
So we showed that above, when we were talking about test case
减少。
reduction.
我们用测试用例做实验。
We were using test cases as experiments.
这根本不会改变代码。
That doesn't change the code at all.
我们还可以插入print语句或断言
We might also insert a print statement or an assertion
进入正在运行的程序来检查
into the running program to check something
关于它的内部状态。
about its internal state.
这使它非常轻微地受到干扰。
That perturbs it very lightly.
我们可以使用调试器设置断点，然后
We might set a break point using a debugger, and then
单步执行代码并查看变量和对象
single step through the code and look at variable and object
价值观。
values.
这些都是很好的实验——轻量级探针。
These are all good experiments-- lightweight probes.
现在很容易尝试，马上，
Now can be very tempting to try, right away,
去修复错误而不是仅仅探测。
to jump to fixing the bug instead of just probing.
但这几乎总是错误的。
But this is almost always the wrong thing to do.
它会导致一种非常特别的猜测和测试
It leads to a kind of very ad hoc guessing and test
一种可以产生
kind of programming, which can produce
糟糕、复杂、难以理解的代码。
awful and complex and hard to understand code.
其次，你的修复可能会掩盖真正的错误
And secondly, your fix may just mask the true bug
而不是真的移除它。
without actually removing it.
你真的想知道什么是错误
You really want to understand what the bug is
决定一个好的解决方案，而不是随机的
and decide on a good fix for it, rather than just randomly
改变并希望它消失。
change and hope that it goes away.
例如，如果你得到一个超出边界的区域
For example, if you're getting an area out of bounds
例外，你真的想了解
exception, you really want to understand
先发生什么事。
what's going on first.
不要只抓住异常而忽略它。
Don't just catch the exception and ignore it.
你想解决真正的问题。
You want to fix the real problem.
这里还有一些其他的技巧可以帮助调试。
And here are some other tips that can help with debugging.
调试实际上是一个搜索过程。
Debugging is really a search process.
所以你可以用二进制搜索来加快速度。
So you can use binary search to speed it up.
所以用最普通的话来说，这些数据
So in most common words, this data
通过三个助手方法。
flows through three helper methods.
所以要进行二进制搜索
So to do a binary search you would divide
将此工作流分成两半，可能是猜测发现了错误
this workflow in half, perhaps guessing that the bug is found
介于这通电话和那通电话之间，
somewhere between this call and that call,
在那里插入探针。
and inserting probes there.
从实验的答案来看，
And then from the answer to that experiment,
你可以把代码进一步分成两半。
you might further divide the code in half.
所以这样重复——特别是
So repeating this way-- particularly
在一个大系统中——你可以很快
in a large system-- you can very quickly
把它隔离到一个可能有虫子的较小区域。
isolate down to a smaller area where the bug might be.
同时考虑优先考虑你可能的假设，
Also think about prioritizing your possible hypotheses,
因为系统的不同部分
because different parts of the system
增加不同的失败可能性。
add different likelihoods of failure.
所以你的密码已经存在一段时间了
So code of yours that has been around for a while
以不同的方式测试了很多--
and tested a lot in various different ways--
不仅仅是通过它的单元测试套件
not only through its unit test suite
也可以通过其他客户端代码实际使用--
but also through actually being used by other client code--
它可能比代码更可信
it's probably more trustworthy than code
你最近添加的。
that you recently added.
同样，出于同样的原因，Java库代码，
Likewise Java library code, for the same reason,
已经存在了很长一段时间，并且测试了很多
has been around much longer and been tested much more
更多的人。
by many more people.
所以它可能比你的代码更可信。
So it's probably more trustworthy than your code.
如果你使用的是Java库之类的
If you're using the Java library and something
似乎出了问题，原因
seems to be going wrong, the cause
可能是你使用它的方式，
is probably the way you're using it,
而不是因为Java库中的错误。
rather than due to a bug in the Java library.
接下来，Java编译器和运行时
Further down, the Java compiler and run time, the operating
系统，你机器的硬件，
system, the hardware of your machine,
越来越值得信赖，因为他们
are increasingly more trustworthy because they're
更多的尝试和考验。
more tried and tested.
所以你应该相信这些低级的
So you should trust these lower levels
直到你找到一个好的理由不去。
until you've found a good reason not to.
另一个好的技术是交换组件。
Another good technique is swapping components.
如果你有一个模块的实现
So if you have an implementation of a module that
满足与模块相同的接口--
satisfies the same interface as the module--
这是同样的规格——而你
it's the same specification-- and you
怀疑这个实现，那么你可以做一件事
suspect that implementation, then one thing you can do
正在尝试替换。
is try swapping in the alternative.
例如，如果你有一个搜索函数
So if you have, for instance, a search function that
有一个二进制实现，您可以
has a binary implementation, you might
希望用更简单的线性实现来替换它。
want to replace it with a simpler linear implementation.
会比较慢，但你可以更确信
It will be slower, but you can be more confident that it
符合其规范。
satisfies its specification.
例如，如果您怀疑数组列表
If you suspect, for example, the array list
实现列表时，可以在链接列表中进行交换。
implementation of lists, you might swap in a linked list.
如果您怀疑Java运行时已损坏，
If you suspect the Java runtime is broken,
您可以切换到另一个版本的Java。
you might switch to a different version of Java.
记住这些都是非常不寻常的假设。
Remember these are very unusual hypotheses.
但它们说明了交换的概念。
But they illustrate the notion of swapping.
你可以浪费很多时间交换
You can waste a lot of time swapping
在组件出现故障时，不要这样做
on failing components, so don't do this
除非你有充分的理由怀疑某个部件，
unless you have good reason to suspect a component,
就像我们在前一段提到的。
like we talked about in the previous paragraph.
你应该确定这是
You should make sure-- this is sort
一件简单的事情——确保你的源代码和对象
of a simple thing-- make sure your source code and object
代码实际上是最新的。
code are actually up to date.
在Eclipse中，您可以通过运行project clean来实现这一点。
In Eclipse, you can do this by running project clean.
你也应该确保，如果你
You Should also make sure, if you
在一个组中工作——在一个有源代码控制的组中工作
are working in a group-- in a team with a source code control
存储库——你应该确保
repository-- you should make sure you've
从存储库中获取代码的最新版本。
got the latest version of the code from the repository.
你可以得到帮助，经常有助于解释
And you can get help it often helps to explain
你对别人的问题。
your problem to someone else.
最后，睡在上面总是个好主意。
Finally, sleeping on it is always a good idea.
如果你太累了，就不去了
If you're too tired, you are not going
成为一个有效的调试器。
to be an effective debugger.
所以一旦你发现了虫子
So now I'll say once you've found the bug
你知道它的原因，第三步
and you understand its cause, the third step
就是想办法解决它。
is to devise a fix for it.
一个好的程序员会
Here's where a good programmer will
避免诱惑，只要拍打一个补丁，然后继续前进。
avoid temptations to just slap a patch on it and move on.
所以你应该扪心自问
So you should ask yourself whether the bug was
一个简单的编码错误——比如变量名拼写错误
a simple coding error-- like a misspelled variable name
或者互换方法参数，
or interchanged method parameters,
或者是设计错误--
or whether it was a design error--
就像方法中的一个坏规范。
like a bad spec in a method.
设计错误表明您需要退后一步思考
Design errors suggest that you need to step back and think
关于你的设计。
about your design.
或者至少考虑一下所有的客户
Or at the very least, consider all the clients
失败的接口。
of the failing interface.
在你的代码中搜索它们，看看它们是否受到这个bug的影响
Search for them in your code to see if they suffer from the bug
我也是。
too.
想想这个虫子有没有亲戚。
Think about whether the bug has any relatives.
如果你发现一个被零除的错误
If you just found a divide by zero error
在这部分代码中，你做了同样的事情吗
in this part of the code, did you do that same thing
密码里还有别的地方吗？
anywhere else in the code?
你的目标是使你的代码安全
Your goal is to try to make your code safe
从未来的虫子身上。
from future bugs like this.
您还应该考虑影响代码的因素
You should also consider what affects your code
你的修好了吗。
will your fix will have.
它会打破其他密码吗？
Will it break any other code?
最后，在你应用了你的修复程序之后，
Finally, after you've applied your fix,
将bug测试用例添加到回归测试套件中
add the bugs test case to your regression test suite
运行所有的测试来保证你自己，首先，
and run all the tests to assure yourself, first,
你修好了，第二，你已经
that you fixed it, and second, that you've
没有引入新的漏洞。
introduced no new bugs.